# 首先我们准备鲜虾500克
First, prepare 500g of shrimps
# 同学们最好选择鲜活的虾勿用死虾
We should use fresh shrimps instead of dead ones
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, start preparing the minor ingredients
# 准备生姜和大蒜各20克切成片之后剁碎备用
Prepare ginger and garlic, 20g each, slice them and mince them
# 同学们切记姜蒜不能用刀拍
Remember not to crack them with knives
# 否则很容易出水
Or else the juice comes out
# 准备大红椒和青椒各小半个切成小粒备用
Perpare halves of red and green bell peppers and dice them
# 加青红椒的目的是给菜品配红绿色
Adding bell peppers would add red and green colors to the dish
# 然后将切好的青红椒粒和姜蒜放在一起
Then put the prepared bell peppers, ginger, and garlic together
# 准备洋葱1小片切成小颗粒备用
Prepare a small piece of onion and dice it
# 加洋葱粒的目的是增加葱香味
This adds the onion flavor to the dish
# 最后准备几根小葱头切碎备用
Then mince a few scallions and set them aside
# 下一步开始制作椒盐
Next prepare the salt and pepper mixture
# 碗中加入适量的食用盐（约80克）
Add some salt to the bowl (around 80g)
# 加入八角1颗
Add one star anise
# 同学们必须将中间的八角籽去除
We need to remove the seeds
# 这样可以防止椒盐产生苦涩味
So that the salt and pepper mixture wouldn't be bitter
# 碗中加入适量的干辣椒（约10克）
Add some dried chili pepper to the bowl (around 10g)
# 加入适量的青花椒（约3克）
Add some Sichuan green peppercorn (around 3g)
# 加入适量的白胡椒（约5克）
Add some white pepper (around 5g)
# 下一步开始炒椒盐
Next, stir-fry the salt and pepper mixture
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后将配好比例的盐下锅
When the wok is heated, put in the salt mixture
# 然后转中小火翻炒10分钟
Then turn to medium-low heat and stir-fry for 10 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将盐和香料炒香
This is to bring out the fragrant smell of salt and spices
# 10分钟之后将其取出
Take it out after 10 minutes
# 然后放入石臼中捣碎备用
And then ground it in quern-stones
# 同学们在捣碎的过程中必须戴好口罩
Make sure to wear a mask when you do it
# 否则眼泪和鼻涕不断
Or you will tear up and develop a running nose
# 中途再加入适量的味精拌匀即可
Add some chicken essence midway
# 不喜欢味精的同学可以不加
If you don't like it, don't add it
# 椒盐倒出之后下一步开始制作
Pour the mixture out for the next step
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水开大火烧开
First we add some water to the wok and boil it with high heat
# 大火烧开之后将鲜虾下锅焯水断生
When the water boils, parboil the shrimps
# 中途加入适量的料酒去除腥味
Add some cooking wine midway to remove the fishy taste
# 等待虾背弯曲之后即可倒出备用
When the shrimps bend, they're ready to be taken out
# 然后我们再次把锅烧热
Then we heat the wok up again
# 锅烧热之后举盆之力加入宽油
When it's heated, add Kuang You
# 然后大火将油温烧至6成热
Then heat the oil up to 60% with high heat
# 中途抓1大把土豆淀粉将虾拌匀
Add a handful of potato starch to mix with the shrimp
# 加淀粉裹虾的目的是让其外酥里嫩
Adding starch to shrimps makes them crispy on the outside and tender on the inside
# 油温6成热之后将裹好淀粉的虾依次下入锅中炸至定型
When the oil is 60% heated, add the shrimps one by one to the wok and fry them
# 鲜虾定型之后捞出备用
After deep frying, take the shrimps out
# 然后用细漏将残渣打捞干净
And use a strainer to remove the remainders from the wok
# 这一步的目的是防止残渣炸糊导致宽油提前报废
This is to prevent the remainders from being over-fried and shortening the lifespan of Kuan You
# 然后转大火将油温升至7成热
Then turn to high heat till the oil is 70% heated
# 油温7成热之后将鲜虾下锅复炸30秒钟
After the oil is 70% heated, deep-fry the shrimps again for 30s
# 复炸30秒之后捞出备用
After frying for 30s, take them out
# 将残渣清理干净之后再把宽油倒出
Remove the remainders once again and pour the Kuan You out
# 然后将切好的辅料全部下锅开中火爆香（姜蒜，辣椒，葱粒）
Then add all precut ingredients to stir-fry in the wok with medium heat (ginger, garlic, chili pepper, and scallions)
# 料头爆香之后加入炸好的鲜虾
When they're ready, add the fried shrimps
# 鲜虾下锅之后开始调味
After adding the shrimps into the wok, start seasoning
# 锅中加入适量的椒盐粉（约4.5克）
Add some salt pepper mixture (around 4.5g)
# 然后转小火翻炒几下即可出锅装盘
Then turn to low heat and stir fry for a bit before it's ready to be served
# 一道外酥里嫩的椒盐虾就制作完成
We've finished making the salt-pepper shrimps that is crispy on the outside and tender on the inside
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，鲜虾可以不用开背
# 第二，捣碎椒盐的时候必须戴口罩
# 第三，嫌麻烦的同学可以直接在超市购买成品椒盐
# 第四，自制椒盐比商品椒盐更有味道且更香
# 第五，不喜欢椒盐中的味精可以不加
# 第六，加淀粉炸虾的目的是防止成菜回软
# 椒盐虾的技术总结完毕
Now we summarize the techniques
First, we don't need to cut fresh shrimps open on the back
Secondly, wear masks when you ground the salt-pepper mixture
Thirdly, if it's too much, you can buy salt-pepper mixture from the supermarket
Fourthly, homemade salt-pepper mixture tastes better
Fifthly, if you don't like chicken essence, don't add it
Sixthly, adding starch to the shrimps prevent them from becoming sloppy when being served
Above is all the techniques for the salt-pepper shrimps